Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- Transcripts of Diaries, 1900-1946
  - Daily diaries and notebooks (Reading room workstation)
    - 1904 June 15-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - 1905 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - 1906 January 1-May 22 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - 1907 June 24-August 9 (Box-folder 41: 7)
    - 1908 June 10-August 30 (Box-folder 41: 8)
    - 1909 June 4-August 4 (Box-folder 41: 9)
    - 1911 September 14-November 16 (Box-folder 41: 10)
      (trip to Japan)
    - 1914 June 3-September 1 (Box-folder 41: 11)
    - 1915 April 20-September 27 (Box-folder 41: 12)
    - 1917 December 15-31 (Box-folder 41: 13)
    - 1918 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 14)
    - 1919 January 1-September 2 (Box-folder 41: 15)
    - 1920 May 2-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 16)
    - 1921 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 17)
    - 1922 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 41: 18)
    - 1923 January 1-October 1 (Box-folder 41: 19)
    - 1924 (Box-folder 41: 20)
    - 1926 September 23-October 24 (Box-folder 41: 21)
    - 1927 May 24-September 24 (Box-folder 41: 22)
    - 1928 September 22-October 30 (Box-folder 41: 23)
    - 1929 March 10-28 (Box-folder 41: 24)
    - 1933 May 30-November 5 (Box-folder 41: 25)
    - 1935 September 9-November 26 (Box-folder 41: 26)
    - 1936 March 5-December 28 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - 1937 June 18-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - 1938 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - 1939 January 1-August 11 (Box-folder 42: 4)
      Includes notes from diary, 1939 and trips, 1935-1939.
    - 1941 December 7-31 (Box-folder 42: 5)
    - 1942 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 6)
    - 1943 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    - 1944 January 1-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 8)
    - 1945
      - January 1–October 15 (Box-folder 42: 9)
      - October 16-December 31 (Box-folder 42: 10)
    - 1946 January 1–September 19 (Box-folder 42: 11)
- Career File, 1911-1946
  Intelligence reports and other historical materials collected during tours of duty in China, lectures and tactical studies prepared at Fort Benning, Georgia, letters received on professional matters and letters received from the public during World War II, loose daily notes written during the 1920s and 1930s, official orders, and correspondence, arranged numerically by file numbers and alphabetically by physical form thereunder.
  - A-1, 1911-1915
    - Circulars, instructions, leave of absence requests, and miscellany, 1911-1915 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - Course description, tests, and grades, including Expert Rifleman's test, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 43: 2)
    - Letters, including of promotion to First Lieutenant of Infantry (May 25, 1911), 1911-1915 (Box-folder 43: 3)
    - Lists of property and financial records, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 43: 4)
    - Memoranda, 1912-1915 (Box-folder 43: 5)
    - Note from Sun Pao Ki to Paul S. Reinsch, 1913 September 15 (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - A-2, 1916-1919
    - Bulletins, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 43: 8)
    - Circulars, instructions, and leave of absence requests, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1918 (Box-folder 43: 10)
    - Daily diary, 1918 February 6 - September 13 (Box-folder 43: 11)
    - Drawings with Joseph W. Stilwell's note on the back, circa 1919 (Box-folder 43: 12)
    - Evaluation report, circa 1919 (Box-folder 43: 13)
    - Letters, including a letter offering Joseph W. Stilwell the position of Military Attaché in Spain, 1917 August 31 (Box-folder 43: 14)
    - List of property received by Joseph W. Stilwell from the Military Training Camp and financial records, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 43: 15)
    - Memoranda, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 43: 16)
    - Notes, including lecture notes on China, Berkeley, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 43: 17)
    - Notification of award of Distinguished Service Medal, undated (Box-folder 43: 18)
    - Organizational chart and classification of work, undated (Box-folder 43: 19)
    - Permits and passes, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 43: 20)
      Includes immunization record.
    - Personal file of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1918 (Box-folder 43: 21)
    - Telegrams, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 43: 22)
      including from U.S. War Dept. announcing the appointment of Joseph W. Stilwell as Lieutenant Colonel, Infantry, (September 11, 1918).
    - Writings by others, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 43: 23)
      Includes an undated poem by Private Webster bidding farewell to Captain Joseph W. Stilwell.
    - Miscellany, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 43: 24)
  - A-3, 1920-1923
    - Circulars, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 43: 25)
    - Letters, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 43: 26)
      Including from United States. Dept. of State designating Joseph W. Stilwell Attaché to the American Legation in Peking, China (July 13, 1920).
    - Maps, including Hunan Road profile, undated (Box-folder 43: 27)
    - Memoranda, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 43: 28)
    - Notes on Urga and related materials, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 43: 29)
    - Printed matter, 1921 (Box-folder 43: 30)
    - Telegrams, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 43: 31)
    - Travel permits, 1922 (Box-folder 43: 32)
    - Miscellany, 1921-1923 (Box-folder 43: 33)
  - A-4, 1924-1927
    - Circulars, 1924-1927 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - Letters, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 44: 2)
    - Map, undated (Box-folder 44: 3)
    - Memoranda, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 44: 4)
    - Reports, including "A Synopsis of the China Situation," by Joseph W. Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 44: 5)
    - Telegrams, 1927 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - Miscellany, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - A-5, 1928-1929
    - Announcements relating to Joseph W. Stilwell's appointment as Chief of Staff and to the Distinguished Service Medal, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 8)
    - Chart, undated (Box-folder 44: 9)
    - Circulars, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 44: 10)
    - Clippings, 1922-1929 (Box-folder 44: 11)
    - Letters, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 44: 12)
    - List of officers, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 13)
    - Map of Eastern Asia, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 14)
    - Memoranda, 1929 (Box-folder 44: 15)
    - Notes, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 16)
    - Record of notification to Chinese military authorities, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 17)
    - Reports, 1928 (Box-folder 44: 18)
    - Telegrams and messages, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 44: 19)
    - Miscellany, 1929 (Box-folder 44: 20)
  - A-6, 1928-1929
    Transcripts of Chinese press.
    - 1928 January-August (Box-folder 44: 21)
    - 1928 August-1929 March (Box-folder 44: 22)
  - A-7, 1930-1931
    - General, 1930 (Box-folder 44: 23)
    - Memoranda, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 44: 24)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 44: 25)
    - Outline for conference, undated (Box-folder 45: 1)
    - Reports, 1930 (Box-folder 45: 2)
      Includes efficiency reports and lectures.
    - Miscellany, 1930 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - A-8, 1931-1932
    - Efficiency reports, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    - Questionnaire on the employment of federal troops to prevent and suppress domestic disturbances, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - A-9, 1931-1933
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS, box 96, folder 2.
    - Chart, undated (Box-folder 45: 6)
    - Circulars, 1933 (Box-folder 45: 7)
    - Clippings, 1932 (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - Distribution list, IV Army Staff, undated (Box-folder 45: 9)
    - Instructions, including by Joseph W. Stilwell on operations and field exercises, 1933 (Box-folder 45: 10)
    - Lectures and notes by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 45: 11-14)
    - Maps and photocopies of war-zone photographs, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 46: 1)
      See also map case, folder 36.
    - Memoranda, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 46: 2)
    - Pamphlet, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - Reports, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 46: 4)
      Including conference reports and report by Joseph W. Stilwell.
    - Telegram, 1933 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - A-10, 1934-1935
    See also Photographs box 96, folder 2.
    - Certificates of appreciation and registration, 1934 (Box-folder 46: 7)
    - Charts and maps, undated (Box-folder 46: 8)
      See also map case, folder 34.
    - Circulars, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 46: 9)
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1935 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    - Genealogical table of the Chinese Emperor, undated (Box-folder 46: 11)
    - Letters of appreciation and congratulations, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 46: 12)
      Including for Joseph W. Stilwell's promotion to the rank of Colonel.
    - Memoranda, 1935 (Box-folder 46: 13)
    - Notes, 1935 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Telegram, 1935 (Box-folder 46: 15)
    - Miscellany, 1935 (Box-folder 46: 16)
  - A-11, 1936
    See also Photographs, PP.
    - Circulars, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 17)
    - Clippings, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 18)
      See also box 111, folder 4.
    - Letters, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 19)
      Including the English translation of a letter from Chiang Kai-shek to Adolf Hitler, September 16, 1936.
    - List of composition and distribution of Chinese troops, 1936 August 1 (Box-folder 46: 20)
    - News releases, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 21)
    - Notes by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 22)
    - Reports on Sino-American and Sino-Japanese relations, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 23)
    - Telegram, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 24)
    - Travel pass for Joseph W. Stilwell, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 25)
    - Miscellany, 1936 (Box-folder 46: 26)
  - A-12, 1937
    See also Photographs, XX.
    - Directive issued by the U.S. Marine Corps, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - Distribution list of Japanese forces, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 2)
    - Letters, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 47: 4)
    - Memoranda, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 5)
    - News release, undated (Box-folder 47: 6)
    - Notes by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 7)
    - Reports, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 8)
    - Telegrams, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - Miscellany, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 10)
      Includes a passport slip in Japanese, a poem, and a postcard.
  - A-12X, 1937
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 11)
    - Letters, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 12)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 47: 13)
    - Memoranda, including for Chiang Kai-shek, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 14)
    - News releases, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 15)
    - Notes by Joseph W. Stilwell, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 16)
    - Reports, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 17)
    - Statements, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 18)
    - Telegrams and coded messages, 1937 (Box-folder 47: 19)
  - A-13, 1938
    See photographs.
    - Certificate of settlement of account, 1938 (Box-folder 47: 20)
    - Circulars, 1938 (Box-folder 47: 21)
    - Distribution list, location, and organization of Chinese and Japanese troops, 1938 (Box-folder 47: 22)
    - Lecture by Chen Cheng to the officers training class at Wuchang, 1938 February 28 (Box-folder 47: 23)
    - Letters, 1938 (Box-folder 47: 24)
    - Memoranda, 1938 (Box-folder 47: 25)
    - Notes and record of daily events, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 1)
    - Reports, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 2-4)
      Includes G-2 reports.
    - Telegrams, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - A-14, 1938
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 7)
    - Lists of army routes, undated (Box-folder 48: 8)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 48: 9)
    - Memoranda, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 10)
    - Notes and notebooks, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 11-12)
    - Reports, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 13-14)
    - Miscellany, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 15)
  - A-15, 1938
    - Article in Hsin Hua Jih Pao, 1938 October 6 (Box-folder 48: 16)
      Regarding Chou En-lai's comments, entitled "How to Save Wuhan."
    - Letters, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 17)
    - Notes, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 18-19)
    - Plan of operation, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 20)
    - Telegrams and coded messages, 1938 (Box-folder 48: 21)
  - A-16. Notes, 1938 (Box-folder 49: 1)
  - A-17, 1939
    - Biographical sketch of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 2)
      Includes identification card, and statement of declaration of household effects.
    - Circulars, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 3)
    - Distribution list of Japanese army, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 4)
    - Letters, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - "Manifesto on Chinese National Policy," by the National Salvation Association in North China, 1939 March 27 (Box-folder 49: 6)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 49: 7)
    - Memoranda, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 8)
    - Notes, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 9)
    - Reports, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 10)
    - Statement by the National Salvation Association in North China regarding Wang Ching Wei's peace proposal, undated (Box-folder 49: 11)
    - Telegrams, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 12)
    - Miscellany, 1939 (Box-folder 49: 13)
  - A-18, 1940
    - Circulars, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 14)
    - Letters, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 15)
    - Memoranda, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 16)
    - Notes, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 17)
    - Press release, undated (Box-folder 49: 18)
    - Printed matter, undated (Box-folder 49: 19)
    - Reports, undated (Box-folder 49: 20)
    - Roster of officers, Seventh Division, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 21)
    - Miscellany, 1940 (Box-folder 49: 22)
  - A-19, 1941
    - Circulars, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 23)
    - Identification card, membership plaque, and special pass, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 24)
    - Letters, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 25)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 49: 26)
    - Memoranda, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 27)
    - Minutes of meetings and reports, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 28)
    - Notes and charts, 1941 (Box-folder 49: 29)
  - A-20, 1942
    - Circulars, 1942 (Box-folder 49: 30)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 49: 31)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 49: 32)
    - Report entitled, "The Campaign in Burma: March 10-June 1 1942,", undated (Box-folder 49: 33)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 49: 34-35)
  - A-21, 1942
    - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Correspondence between Claire Lee Chennault, Claire Booth Luce, Clayton L. Bissell, Joseph W. Stilwell, Shang Chen, T. V. Soong, Willard Wyman, and others, 1942 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Memoranda, including from Joseph W. Stilwell to T. V. Soong, 1942 December (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - Notes, 1942 (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - Plan of operations, 1942 (Box-folder 50: 5)
    - Reports, 1942 (Box-folder 50: 6)
    - Telegrams, messages, and order, 1942 (Box-folder 50: 7)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - A-22, 1943
    - Address by Chiang Kai-shek to the Chinese New First Army in India, 1943 November 30 (Box-folder 50: 9)
    - Article, "Books Authors and Personalities of the Hour Broadcast,", 1943 November 12 (Box-folder 50: 10)
    - Circulars, 1943 (Box-folder 50: 11)
    - Letters, 1943 (Box-folder 50: 12)
      Including from Joseph W. Stilwell to Ho Ying-chin (March 20), and from Louis Mountbatten to Joseph W. Stilwell (December 18); and fragment of a letter from George C. Marshall noting Joseph W. Stilwell’s accomplishments under difficult circumstances.
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 50: 13)
    - Memoranda, 1943 (Box-folder 50: 14)
      Including from John Davies to Joseph W. Stilwell on “The Indian Problem: Fall and Winter, 1942-1943,” and “Policy Conflicts among the United Nations,” September 1943, and to the Ambassador on “The Stilwell Mission,” March 9, 1943.
    - Notes, 1943 (Box-folder 50: 15)
    - Report on the Chinese School of Mechanization, Hungkiang, undated (Box-folder 50: 16)
    - Miscellany, 1943 (Box-folder 50: 17)
      See also box 111, folder 1.
  - A-23, 1943-1944
    - Circulars, 1944 (Box-folder 50: 18)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 50: 19)
      Including of President Franklin D. Roosevelt with Patrick J. Hurley.
    - Lists, including of casualties, undated (Box-folder 50: 20)
    - Maps, circa 1944 (Box-folder 50: 21)
      See also map case, folder 29.
    - Memoranda, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 50: 22)
    - Messages, 1944 (Box-folder 50: 23)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1944 (Box-folder 50: 24)
    - Notes, 1944 (Box-folder 50: 25)
    - Organizational chart, undated (Box-folder 50: 26)
    - Printed matter, undated (Box-folder 50: 27)
    - Reports, 1944 (Box-folder 52: 28)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 50: 29)
  - A-24, 1944-1945
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - Memoranda, including of conversation, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 2)
    - Messages, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 3)
    - Notes, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 4)
    - Outline of the status of negotiations with Chiang Kai-shek, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 5)
    - Printed matter, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 55: 6)
    - Records relating to Joseph W. Stilwell's recall, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 7)
    - Reports, including on general situation, 1944, undated (Box-folder 51: 8)
    - Speech by Chiang Kai-shek, 1944 July 5 (Box-folder 51: 9)
  - A-25, 1944
    - Lists, including of papers by Joseph W. Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 51: 10)
    - Memorandum from John S. Service, May 5, 1944, on the speech by Sun Fo to the Legislature, 1944 April 15 (Box-folder 51: 11)
    - Notes, including excerpts from the "Black Book,", undated (Box-folder 51: 12)
    - Order, undated (Box-folder 51: 13)
      Including organizational chart and instructions, issued by Chiang Kai-shek appointing Joseph W. Stilwell as Field Commander of the Ground and Air Forces of the Republic of China.
    - Reports, 1944 (Box-folder 53: 14)
      Including reports of the situation in China and summary of background and circumstances of Joseph W. Stilwell's recall.
  - A-26, War diary, 1944 (Box-folder 51: 15)
  - A-27, 1945
    - Articles by others, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 16)
    - Certificates of termination and of personal property shipped, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 17)
    - Circular, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 18)
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 19)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 20)
    - Lists of officers and recipients of the Medal of Honor, and schedule of inspection trips, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 21)
    - Maps, undated (Box-folder 51: 22)
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 23)
    - Messages and telegrams, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 24)
    - Notes, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 25)
    - Remarks by Donald Armstrong, 1945 May 29 (Box-folder 51: 26)
    - Reports, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 27)
    - Speech of Walter Judd to the U.S. Congress. House of Representatives, March 15, 1945 (Box-folder 51: 28)
    - Statement regarding some of Brigadier General William D. Old's troop carrier command activities, undated (Box-folder 51: 29)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 51: 30)
  - A-28, 1945
    - Biographical sketch of Joseph W. Stilwell, circa 1945 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Guide to office procedures, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 3)
    - Interview of H. C. Ingles, Chief Signal Officer, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 4)
      Including by Joseph W. Stilwell.
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 5)
    - Notes, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 6)
    - Reports, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 7-11)
    - Roster of general officers in the Pacific, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 12)
    - Telegrams, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 13)
  - A-29, 1945
    - Certificates noting the presence of Joseph W. Stilwell at the formal surrender of the Japanese forces to the Allied Powers and of membership in the Friendly Burma Road Jeeping and Marching Association, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 14)
    - Chart describing the 325 days of continuous fighting with the IV Corps in the Italian campaign, 1944 June – 1945 May (Map-case folder 27)
    - Clippings, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 15)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 52: 16)
    - Record and related procedure of Japanese surrender, 1945 (Box-folder 52: 17)
      See also box 111, folder 8.
  - A-30, 1945
    - Letter from Toshio Nomi to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1945 September 4 (Box-folder 52: 18)
    - Letters from Toshisada Takada to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1945 September 3 (Box-folder 52: 19)
    - Map, undated (Box-folder 52: 20)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 52: 21)
    - Telegram to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding the Japanese surrender, 1945 August 10 (Box-folder 52: 22)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 52: 23)
  - A-31, 1945
    - Incoming and outgoing messages, 1945 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Memoranda, 1945 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Office file of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1945 (Box-folder 53: 3-6)
  - A-32, 1945 August-October (Box-folder 53: 7-8)
    Correspondence between Joseph W. Stilwell and Richard Lockard, Kenneth Meheran, C. W. Nimitz, S. H. Patton, Larry Stapleton, and othersCorrespondence between Joseph W. Stilwell and Richard Lockard, Kenneth Meheran, C. W. Nimitz, S. H. Patton, Larry Stapleton, and others.
  - A-33, 1945-1946
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS/F.
    - Chart, undated (Box-folder 53: 9)
    - Circulars and schedule, 1945 (Box-folder 53: 10)
    - Correspondence, including with Dwight D. Eisenhower and Hugh de Lacy, 1946 (Box-folder 53: 11-12)
    - Identification card and pass, 1946 (Box-folder 53: 13)
    - Memoranda, 1946 (Box-folder 53: 14)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 53: 15)
    - Pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 53: 16)
    - Press releases, 1946 (Box-folder 53: 17)
    - Reports, including of first atomic bomb test, Bikini Atoll (July 1, 1946) (Box-folder 53: 18)
    - Speech by Chiang Kai-shek (English translation) at the closing session of the Political Consultation Conference, 1946 January 31 (Box-folder 53: 19)
    - Speeches, 1946 July 26 (Box-folder 53: 20)
      "America's Responsibility for Civil War in China," by Hugh de Lacy; "General Marshall's Mission and the Civil War in China," by Ellis E. Patterson; and "The Role of America's Lend-Lease in China's Civil War," by Charles R. Savage.
  - A-33X, 1945 December – 1946 January
    - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 53: 21-23)
      Including with Harold Ickes, John P. Davies, Richard Lockard, and T. G. Hearn.
    - List of addresses, holiday roster, and papers, 1945 (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Memoranda, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 54: 2)
    - News release, 1945 (Box-folder 54: 3)
      Includes related material.
    - Telegrams and messages, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 54: 4)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - A-34, 1945 January - 1946 February (Box-folder 54: 6-8)
    Correspondence relating to requests for autographs, photos, and shoulder patches.
  - A-35, 1946 February-April
    - Circulars (Box-folder 54: 9)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 54: 10)
    - Press release (Box-folder 54: 11)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 54: 12)
  - A-36, 1946 May–August
    - Circulars (Box-folder 54: 13)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 54: 14-16)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 54: 17)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 54: 18)
  - A-37, 1946 August–October
    - Circular (Box-folder 54: 19)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 54: 20)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 54: 21)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 54: 22)
  - A-38, 1946
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 55: 1-2)
    - List of invitations (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - A-39, 1946 March–April (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - A-40, 1946 June–October (Box-folder 55: 6)
- Personal and Family File, 1889-1972
  Correspondence with family and friends, domestic records of various kinds, and school and family records, arranged numerically by file numbers and alphabetically by physical form thereunder.
  - B-1, 1889-1931
    - Clippings and printed matter, 1889-1931 (Box-folder 55: 7)
      Includes a letter to the editor, The Statesman, August 31, 1889, by Benjamin W. Stilwell; an obituary of Benjamin W. Stilwell, To Serve New York, undated; and an announcement of Joseph W. Stilwell’s athletic abilities, undated.
    - High School certificate and report cards, 1895-1899 (Box-folder 55: 8)
      Includes a postcard depicting Yonkers High School, New York, undated.
    - Letters
      - Unidentified; undated letter from Benjamin W. Stilwell to his family, 1899-1902 (Box-folder 55: 9)